はっ！
Heavens Arena.
それ以上…　こっちへ来るな。
The 251-story, 991-meter building
プフ！
is a mecca for fighters.
チッ。
When combatants win a fight,
they may advance by one class, and receive a corresponding reward.
そんなイチかバチかは　ごめんだ。
Today, I'll beat Killua-chan for my sixth win.
解せませんね。
Tomorrow, I'll beat Gon-chan
for my seventh win.
その娘を助けたいから 彼は　そこにいるのでしょう？
Then I just need to find three more chumps.
それが　まるで　彼女に 危害を及ぼすかのような口ぶり。
And I'll be a Floor Master.
一体…。 お前には　関係ない。
I'll get all the wealth and glory to
set me up for the rest of my life.
俺は　充電終えたら ゴンとこ戻る。
Use Nen, and I will kill you. Make a sound, and I will kill you.
お前は ナックルんとこ行ってくれ。
If you understand, slowly close your eyes.
プフが結界から出た以上 旦那がやられた可能性が高い。
Do you know what happens
if you break your word?
状況見て　撤退含めて ナックルと決めてくれ。
If you know, slowly open your eyes.
お…　お前らは？
Look at me in the mirror, and listen carefully.
最悪　心中だな。
Never show your filthy face to us again.
ウソだよ！　大丈夫！
That's a promise.
俺には　「カイト」っつう 最強の呪文が　あっからな。 こっちは任せろ！
Power x To x Avenge
ホントかよ
There are many who would use
なら　何で　お前　あの時…
underhanded tactics to become a Floor Master.
あんな悲しそうな顔 してたんだよ
On the other hand, Gon has concentrated on improving
his Nen and growing stronger.
いいんだな？
And tonight, he has his battle with Sadaso.
言えねえし 言わねえんだよな？ じゃあ　聞けねえし 聞かねえよ？
His eyes reflected his underworld affiliations.
お前には　関係ない。
The second he looked at me, I felt a difference in strength
黙ってろ。
that made me realize my
helplessness against him.
黙れ？
It was a mistake to underestimate him, and to assume he was some normal kid.
フッ　お邪魔ですか。 ピトー
What should we do?
ここは　あなたに 任せることにしましょう。
I'm still in.
動くな。 そこにいろ。
I'll do whatever it takes.
鱗粉を使って　人を操るんだろ？
I'm this close to becoming a Floor Master.
そこから　一歩も動くな。
Ten victories in the 200s win you the right to challenge a Floor Master.
プフ　頼む。 正気ですか？
Should you triumph, you get
an entire floor to yourself.
何もせず　ただ　ここに？ そんな娘のために。 王のためだ！
And once you've earned the
title of Floor Master, you can lecture, serve as an advisor, or start a new martial arts school.
言うことを聞いてくれ。
You can live off the title for
the rest of your life.
何があったのです？
Will that kid try threatening us?
明らかに あなたの顔つきが違います
The boy doesn't know my power.
私が閉じ込められている間に 一体　何が？
As long as we're careful, we can handle him. You're wrong.
約束しましょう。 私は　ここを一歩も動かない。
I can threaten you whenever I want.
代わりに教えていただきたい。 ここで起きた全て！　一部始終を！
Whenever and wherever I choose... When you're sound asleep...
さりげなく 慎重に　お願いします
Now, listen up.
失敗すれば…　修羅場 それだけのこと
You have to follow the rules. Without rules, we are the ones who would benefit.
つかんだ！
Right.
もう一回やれば 完全に自分のものにできる！
Time has run out for Sadaso. Gon wins by default! What? Again?
怒りだ！　怒りをためろ！
What is Sadaso doing?
破壊と構築の同居！
Okay, Gon-kun is fighting Gido today.
それを肉体で表現するのだ！
Killua-kun will be facing Riehlvelt.
ユピーは　まだ気付いていない
Are you feeling all right? Yes.
なぜ　相反する感情が 同時に成り立つか
Gon-kun, this will be your
second match with Gido.
そして　己の現状に
So you shouldn't require much advice. Do you have a plan?
怒りとは… 怒りとは まき散らすものではなく
Uh-huh. Um, Wing-san, actually...
何かに向けるものなのだ!!
I'm planning to use this.
ハハっ！　ハッハッハッ…!!
I see...
ハッハッハッ…！ ＯＫ　ＯＫ！
In their previous encounter, Gon ended up in the hospital, but what will happen this time?
外れ　ＯＫ！
Today, he's carrying a fishing rod.
もっとだ　もっと！ 俺をもっと怒らせろ!!
How does he plan to use it?
オラ!!
How does he intend to fight?
ポットクリンの利息が 現状のまま 上がって行く前提で計算し
But Gido was also prepared, as he's
already using Tornado Top!
ユピーが最低限の消費で オーラの使用を控えたとしても
If Gon charges in, he'll be in the same position as before.
今から　３分５０秒後
So he anticipated that.
念能力の使用が不可能となる 瀬戸際まで来ていた
I know exactly what you're thinking... Once I've begun to spin,
it's extremely hard to stop me.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。 残り１０体
Thus, the logical course would be a preemptive attack before I start.
あっ！
If you won't make a move, I'll go first.
いよいよ土壇場だな
Shotgun Blues! Shotgun Blues
奴は　どうやら　俺を 最後に料理する気らしいな
He can dispatch his tops, even while spinning? This technique is nothing like Battle Waltz.
ならば　１秒でも長く あがいてやる！
Every top will be aiming for you. You can't avoid them all!
ユピーの目の届く範囲に 全兵士を配していたのは
What?
モラウからもユピーの動きが 把握できるからであったが
He stopped them! Did you see that?
兵士を広範囲に散乱させるのが 不可能なほど
Wow... Incredible! He stopped the tops in their tracks!
モラウの疲労が深刻なレベルに 達したからでもあった
He clearly isn't the same
person as two months ago!
霧散してしまう もう少しのはずなんだ
His Nen defense is far stronger now. I can't win with my tops?
なのに…
Gon's reflexes are good enough
なのに…　クソ！
to let him use his rod to knock down any tops
体が　心が　動かねえ…
that are stupid enough to come straight at him. But he chose to use Ren
なけなしの精神力を 振り絞っても 立ち上がることさえ　かなわない
to deal more psychological damage.
文字通りの限界は ユピーの破産よりも早く訪れた
He must be pretty mad about how they used Zushi.
残り…　ゼロ
Well, what technique will Gon use?
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
If he's attacking with that fishing rod, I'd guess he'll try to snag me, to stop my spinning.
怒りのエネルギーを
But it won't be that simple.
ハァ　ハァ…。 フン
There he goes... Straight for Gido!
どう見ても 死にかけの小バエだぜ。 なのに
I knew it. But that won't do you any good!
すげぇな　お前ら。
Oh, his attack missed!
戦闘のさなかに 驚異的な速さで進化し
What were you aiming at?
さらに大きく引き離したはずの ユピーが抱いていた感情は
What?!
敗者への称賛であった 自身がユピーに持つ印象から 考えれば
Unbelievable... Gon pulled up the floor, with Gido on it!
うまく言えねえが すげぇって思ったからこそ
Wait!
ゲームオーバーだ…
G-Gon has broken Gido's prosthetic leg.
まっ　一撃で楽にしてやるから 動くなよ？
Gido can no longer continue to fight.
今の　こいつなら 殺られてもいいか
If you're willing to do whatever it takes, I won't hold back.
…って思っちまってる じゃあな。
And if you touch Zushi again, I'll smash your face in!
フ…。
Gon was able to avenge his initial loss!
瞬間移動じゃなかったのか？
Okay, it's my turn now.
奴は 俺が突き刺そうとした瞬間に 消えた
All right, up next is our main event...
俺は　奴らの仲間に
Killua versus Riehlvelt!
テレポートできる奴がいると 思っていたが 消える瞬間にも 仲間は見えなかった
Because Sadaso forfeited the previous match, this will technically be Killua's debut 200s match.
それ以前に　テレポートなら 消えた後に刺しても 傷つけられるはずがない
What will his strategy be? You're the ones who broke your promise.
消えたのに刺せた
I won't let you win now.
…ってことは　透明なだけ？ 透ける能力か！
His eyes reflected his underworld affiliations.
奴に　その能力があるならば とっくに使っていたはず！
An underworld dweller, huh?
つまり　奴らの仲間に 自分だけじゃなく 仲間も透明にできる奴がいて…
This boy may be a professional there, but Heavens Arena is my turf.
俺が突き刺す直前に グラサンを助けようとした …ってことだ 傷は　深い！
I'll show him that, on this square stage, I'm better.
来た！
Begin!
血が！ ユピーに見えちまってる！
He disappeared?
奴が　もう一度 剣を振り上げたら
Behind me!
俺だけでも逃げなきゃ！
Aura Burst!
くっ…　息も限界！
Wow, he's dashed out of harm's way!
チクショウ！
He uses the propulsion created
by releasing his stored aura
なぜ　出て来ちまったんだよ！ お前が今 やらなきゃいけねえのは
Twin Snakes:
もう　逃げも隠れもしねえ。
There it is!
俺が相手だ。
His Song of Defense...
だから…。 見逃してやってくれ！
Riehlvelt protects himself with two
whips moving at ridiculous speed, while he awaits his opportunity to strike.
ナックルが　拳ではなく 言葉に賭けたのは
You planned to attack first and take the lead. Too bad it didn't work...
ユピーのひと言に 己が揺さぶられたからであった
Now that I've switched to this stance, you have no chance of winning. Why not?
フッ　ムチャクチャだな。
A normal person can't even see the whips move!
交換条件にすら　なってねえ。 くっ…。 答えは…。
And this small ring offers no
means to hide or escape.
こいつを消せば　話は別だ。
Take this!
これが対等の条件ってもんだろ？ くっ…。
Sorry, but I'm not a normal person. What?!
や…　やめろ！
But...
ナックル！　ふざけんじゃねえぞ！ 死力を絞ったモラウの叫びは
Thunder Snake!
俺は　ほっとけ！
So I have a present for you... Together, my whips carry a
one million volt current.
ナックル!!
Enough to paralyze and
incapacitate the largest of men.
か…　まう…　な…。
Any fool who resists my whips will fall prey to Thunder Snake!
モラウの　シュートの
I'm accustomed to electrical currents
お前の！　命懸けの全て!!
from the torture training I've endured. It has no effect on me.
ナックルが思いとどまれば まだ２人で戦える
But that just means I can bear the pain. It still hurts.
そのためには　まだ 姿を見せるわけにはいかない
That's why I'm a little pissed.
その思いでモラウから離れた メレオロンの判断は…
If you fall from that height, you'll die! What do you want?
ナックル！ ナックル！
P-Please catch me!
これで　もうない ユピーを倒す　すべが
Man, you realize how painful it is now, idiot?
な…　ぜ！ 血に染まったモラウの姿が シュートの姿と重なり
Riehlvelt has been knocked unconscious. Our winner is Killua!
オレを殺れ!!
You're up next.
やなこった。
Uh-huh, June 10th.
待てコラ！　どこ行く気だ！
My win was only possible
because of who I am...
あっ？ 王のとこに決まってんだろうが。
If you're hit by those electric whips, you'll be knocked out cold.
お前も一緒に来るか？
Yeah.
無理だろ　バカが。
What's your plan?
そいつの能力
Don't worry. I have an idea.
瞬間移動じゃねえんだろ。
Oh? In spirit, you were fighting
even as you watched me.
医者に運ばねえと 交換条件の意味 なくなるだろうが！
I guess you prefer actual combat
to being a spectator.
てめぇらみてぇなザコども
It appears that the damage
何度　来ようが俺が蹴散らす！ 理解していながら それを実行しない自分に
Gido suffered in his match
with Gon was so severe, he hasn't returned for today's fight.
ユピーは　怒りとは異質の いら立ちを覚えていた
Killua wins by default.
今は　殺るまでもねえ！ それだけのことだ！
After losing to Killua, Riehlvelt's record stands at 5-3,
leaving him no more chances.
クソ！　プフのが　うつった
As you know, after four losses,
you're out of the contest.
戦いの中で 敵から教わった念能力の深遠
You'll have to start over from the beginning.
それは　乏しかった ユピーの個を大きく揺らし
He appears wary of Gon's speed, as he already has his whips out.
怒りを別個に蓄積する　すべを 覚えたことで 冷えた感情は　逆に
Meanwhile, Gon isn't carrying his fishing rod...
物事を単純に 考えられなくさせていた
How does he plan to fight?
奴らを糧に　ためた怒り なのに　なぜだ？
Oh, Riehlvelt opened with Song of Defense! Riehlvelt is attempting to end the fight now!
これは成長なのか？ ユピーには分からなかった
Amazing... He pried a floor tile loose by himself!
しかし　ナックルは…
And then he threw it! Aura Burst!
負けた…　完全に…
He left that escape route open on purpose. What?
ナックル！
However, Gon has already anticipated him.
早く　旦那を！
When you try to escape,
every fraction of a second counts.
ボス　さぁ…。 俺に構うなって言ったろうが…。
And since there isn't time to change direction, you're forced to move forward...
行け！
And when you dash quickly,
you're usually off-balance.
お前ら…なら…　まだやれる！
His only option is to stop the whips.
やることを…　やれ！
That's where you get him...
俺　もう…　あいつを
This is the switch?
駆除する標的としては 見れないっす。
Let's see... I'll turn the power to maximum.
お前…。
S-Stop...
こっちの真剣を くんでくれたんすよ！
Switch Stop it!
悪い奴じゃなかった！
on!
倒す理由なんて。 王だよ
Just kidding.
ノヴさ…。
Riehlvelt has fallen unconscious.
王が　タクトを振れば 奴らは悪魔にでもなるさ。
Gon-san!
もう間に合わない。 お役ごめんさ　お前達もな。
Yes, that truly was impressive. I can see the progress you've made
ククク…。 パームは？ いや　まだ…。
from these last two fights.
そうか。 どうする？　もう一度 俺が来られるとは　限らないぞ。
Feel free to pick a time and place...
見ての通り　このザマだ。
I shall be your opponent.
行くか。 パームを捜すのか？ いや　それは　後だ。
Their fight will soon begin.